No way!
He... he did it! Tanjiro did it!
Damn it! You beat me!
It's not over yet! If I relax for even a second, I'll lose my focus!
I have to dig in my heels and keep pushing with all my strength!
Not just with your arms! That's right, the key is to use your core!
You've got more muscles in your lower body than your upper body!
Aaaahhh!
Eeeeh! Eeeeh!
Tempura! Tempura!
I'm coming through!
Eeeeh! Eeeeh!
Ah! Inosuke managed to move his boulder too!
This sucks!
That leaves only me! This really sucks!
Eeeeh! Eeeeh! Eeeeh!
JunTaro?
What do you want?
I still haven't moved my boulder yet.
They're gonna move on without me at this rate.
So would you mind not rushing me?
Eeeeh!
Ow! Hey! That hurt!
Eeeeh! Eeeeh!
Huh? What? A letter?
Since I've got Whenever You Were
I was just as long as I was
At the beat, but happy
It's coming if I can admit
1973, momento, that moment
Our Dh gelmiş Dad
There can be a funeral
As though the frameless world
I can end after thereacting
My soul knows nothing
Oh
I did it
That's one show
That means
I'm training
With Mr. Himejima
It's over
Huh?
Oh no
I'm dehydrated
I didn't drink enough water
To offset the bucket loads of sweat
My body's now covered in
Zenitsu
Inosuke
Mr. Murata
I feel like I'm about to die
Somebody help me
Mr. Himejima
Thank goodness
Namu Amidabutsu
Am I dead?
No
I'm alive
Thank you for saving me
You have now completed
Your boulder training
And in addition to that
You made the right choice
Back at the village
For that you have
My utmost respect
Village
What the
That's enough
Back when the swordsmith village was attacked
You prioritized the lives of the villagers
Over the life of your younger demon sister that you cherish
I just
No need to be ashamed
You are an extraordinary swordsman
You should be proud of the virtuous actions you took that day
Sorry
I can't
Because Nezuko made that choice
It wasn't me
I was indecisive
And because of that the villagers nearly died
I haven't earned your respect
While children are pure and innocent creatures
Their sense of self is often lacking and weak
They're prone to lying and have no qualms about being cruel
They are selfishness personified
However
Just as I thought
This child is different
Throughout my entire life
I've tried my best to keep myself on the right path
But sometimes I get lost
And when I do
Someone always leads me back to it
So in the end
I never stray too far off
That day
Nezuko guided me back
And so
I'm asking you not to acknowledge me so quickly
Oh right
Thank you for the water
And thank you for training me up till now
I've learned a lot
You have dispelled my doubts
Regardless of what anyone says
Know you have my utmost respect
Tanjiro Kamado
Wait
But why
I don't deserve it
Because when I was younger
Years ago
I was raising some orphan children at a temple
Kasunori
You're late
Sorry
I had to use the bathroom
Teacher
This is quite a feast today
Indeed
I happened to run into a dried fish vendor
He was kind enough to give his unsold goods to me for cheap
Let us give thanks to this kind person
And let us also give thanks to Ryotaro and Asami who cooked us this meal
You better appreciate it
Hey Ryotaro
Is something wrong?
I want you to have my fish
Please take it teacher
Please
You're too skinny
You need to eat more food
Oh I see
What a sweet child you are, Sayo
I appreciate your concern
But as I've undergone a strict training regimen
Being hungry isn't troublesome
Now then
Go sit down and enjoy your fish
Right
I may not look strong
But don't judge a book by its cover
Fine
I'll take the fish then
No you won't
This fish is for teacher and teacher only
Thank you for the food
Although none of us were related by blood
We all got along well
Helping each other out
And living like a real family
I truly believed in my heart
That I would continue to live like that for the rest of my life
However, one night
A child broke one of our rules by failing to return to the temple before dark
When he encountered a demon
So in order to preserve his own life
He made a deal with the demon
His life would be spared
In exchange for my life and eight children
In the area where I was born and raised
The rumors of demons and the threat they posed persisted
And so every night
I would burn wisteria incense outside the temple
However, that night
The child extinguished the incense and destroyed the burner
Then guided the demon inside the temple where we slept
Who's awake at this hour?
Four of the children were killed instantly
I did all that I could to protect the remaining four
But three of the children panicked
And didn't do as I instructed
Rather than rely on me, they fled
Their throats were slashed open in a heartbeat
Back then I was thin
I wasn't eating nearly enough
I was also quite timid
Now that I think about it
I had never so much as raised my voice
In summation
I was but an unarmed blind man
I was hardly an intimidating presence
So it's no wonder the kids chose to run
Mr. Himejima is blind?
It was only the youngest girl, Sayo
Who against all her instincts listened to me in the moment
Sayo alone hid behind me
Hoping that I could protect her
So I fought
I fought believing that no matter what
I had to protect Sayo with my life
No climate change
People have been
Let it be
No
Striking a living creature in such a violent manner felt like hell to me.
I'll never forget how revolting that feeling was for as long as I live.
For the first time in my life, I was clenching my fist to throw punches with full force,
and my strength was terrifying even to me.
Had that demon not attacked me, I would have gone my whole life never knowing how fearsome a strength I possessed.
Again and again I continued to slam my fists against the demon's head until daybreak.
That night, I lost nearly everything, and my body was left broken.
I had risked my life to protect little Sayo.
When help arrived on the scene, this is what she told them.
That man is a monster.
He's the one who did it.
Who killed everyone.
No way.
The terror of that experience must have left her confused.
She was just a child of four after all.
Who could blame her for it?
That's just the kind of creatures children are.
Despite what happened, I was desperate.
I needed Sayo to appreciate what I had done.
What I wanted to hear her say above all else was,
Thank you for fighting for me.
I felt just hearing those words would have been enough to save me.
But these are children we're talking about.
All they can do is think of themselves.
The demon's corpse soon turned to dust and vanished.
All that remained were the bodies of the orphans I cared for.
Soon after the incident transpired, I was thrown into prison for murder.
If the Master hadn't intervened on my behalf,
I would have been executed at some point.
It's because of what happened that I became distrustful of nearly everyone around me.
Needless to say, I was suspicious of you, too.
Even the people who present themselves as being virtuous
can turn against you when it matters most.
But you, you never ran off.
You never turned your gaze away.
You never lied.
You were pure and single-minded.
And while that may seem simple enough,
few can remain that way, regardless of the situation they're in.
You're a special child, Tanjiro Kamato.
I say this as someone who's observed scores of people with the eyes of my soul.
Thus, I cannot be wrong.
When it comes to what lies ahead, all of us hold our own doubts.
From now on, I, too, will help you, however I can, to guide you along your path.
I'll do my best.
Thank you for everything.
All your training here with me is now complete.
Say what you will about him, but Mr. Himejima's a good guy.
He said I couldn't be his Tsukuko because I didn't have the talent.
But when he sensed I was eating demons, he made me his apprentice.
He even introduced me to Miss Kocho and had her check on my condition.
Wow, I had no idea.
Miss Kocho gave me this really sour look, though, and lectures me whenever I see her.
Hey, wait!
We were saving that one for Zenitsu to eat.
Huh?
If he's a no-show, that means he doesn't want it, right?
Know what I think?
That jerk's probably got the runs right now.
No.
Actually, if it was anything, I'd say he would be starving.
Give it a rest already.
All you ever do is worry about other people.
You know, you seem to be pretty stubborn yourself, so I thought she'd give you a hard time.
But she didn't.
So why did you get a pass?
Well, if I had no breathing techniques, I have a feeling I'd be in the same boat as you.
Oh, how are you physically, though?
Knowing Miss Shinobu, she's only doing it because she's worried about your health.
I think so.
Definitely.
After I'm done eating, I'm going to Mr. Giyu's.
Are you coming along, too?
Sorry, but I can't.
I haven't been able to move my boulder at Cho yet.
Yeah, well, I'm almost done, you know.
That's just because I can't use breathing techniques.
You really can't use breathing techniques?
What a loser!
What did you just call me?
Bottom feet hurt me out!
Calm down, you two!
Get off!
I was thinking maybe we could talk along the way if you were coming with me.
About what?
About the wind, Hashira.
You know, about your older brother.
I've been thinking.
Hey, Zenitsu!
There you are!
Did you ever get your boulder to move?
No.
Not yet.
I see.
Well, I'm heading to my next training session.
Are you alright?
It's just, you haven't said very much over the last few days.
Is that right?
That's great.
Give it your all.
As for me...
It's clear now.
What I have to do, no matter what stands before me.
Hey, did something happen?
If there's anything I can do to help...
Tanjiro.
Just focus on what you need to do.
But...
I'm worried.
You really are a good person, aren't you, Tanjiro?
Thank you.
No matter what it may take, this is something I have to do.
Is Zenitsu really going to be okay?
Not to mention Nezuko.
Wow.
I feel bad leaving her with someone else for so long.
I hope she's not feeling lonely.
Huh?
Let's see.
So, right now, I'm here?
Then Mr. Giyu's place should be close by, right?
Huh?
So quick!
Wind breathing, first four, dust whirlwind cutter!
Hold on.
I can see and follow their movements.
What's wrong? Come on!
What happened to all that talk about not being like the rest of us, huh?
It's just I'm not like the rest of you.
Oh, about that, that's not what he meant.
Water breathing.
Fourth form, striking tide.
You're too slow!
Seventh form, drop ripple thrust.
Fifth form, cold mountain wind!
Tch, tch, fine.
Guess we'll kill each other with our bare hands then.
Wait, wait, wait!
Please wait a second!
You can't just kill each other!
Tell me a favor and shut the hell up!
And what happened to that restraining order you have?
Oh, I get it. You've been spying on us, you lousy scumbag!
Is this about Red Bean Mochi?
If that's the case, I promise I can make you enough to fill you up, okay?
You're messing with me, aren't you, brat?
What? No, no, I'm serious!
After all, you do love Red Bean Mochi, right?
I remember back when you were training me at your place.
I could always count on catching a whiff of mochi rice and red bean paste.
Smells so good!
There was always this lovely scent of matcha tea and Red Bean Mochi, so I thought...
Hey, Shinazugawa, you like Red Bean Mochi?
Red Bean Mochis sure are yummy, aren't they?
Do you like smooth beans or chunky?
My grandma's Red Bean Mochi was my favorite!
Red Bean Mochi was my favorite part of the game.
I don't know.
What the...
Huh?
Mr. Giyu?
Shinazugawa left.
He got frustrated and stormed off.
Oh, I see.
So why were you two fighting?
We weren't fighting.
It's just part of Hashira training.
We spar with each other.
Hashira versus Hashira.
Wow, I had no idea.
That's why you used wooden swords.
It was sparring.
Oh, I get it now.
Sorry I interrupted.
No, don't worry about it.
You hardly interrupted anything.
We barely talked, and he was angry the whole time.
But I found out what Shinazugawa's favorite food is.
From now on, I think I'll hide a Red Bean Mochi in my sleeve.
And every time I see him, give him one.
Hey!
That's a great idea!
If I do, maybe then we'll become friends.
I'll do the same!
Yeah, don't bother, idiots.
I'll do the same thing.
Bastards.
Where'd they go off to anyway?
They can't be out.
Iguro and Tokido at the same time?
If running those losers into the ground is all I do, I'll get rusty.
Is this about Red Bean Mochi?
Tanjiro Kamado.
If only that pumpkin put a damper on things.
Bastard!
What the hell's his deal anyway?
All he does is get in my way, stupid brat!
What the hell is this?
We've been infiltrated.
That way.
We can't punishment.
We'll be right back.
So...
You found me.
Nice to finally meet you.
So...
It's about time...
Uzan...
Good...
Goodness gracious...
I didn't expect...
I didn't expect you to look so hideous...
Ubuyashiki...
Today we're...
Today we're talking about Mr. Shinazugawa.
What the hell is this?
You got some business with me, Kamado?
Well, I wouldn't call it business.
If you don't, then get the hell out of my sight!
Say...
All right, here's a Taisho-era secret.
Mr. Shinazugawa raises Japanese rhinoceros beetles.
And his favorite food is red bean mochi.
Red bean mochi?
Did you mention red bean mochi again?
Next, the final episode!
The Hashira unite!
Get back here!